Preliminary Guide to the Hastings Center Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hastings Center records
1969-1988
MS 1695
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
39
(39 boxes)
The records consist of minutes, annual reports, grant files, and correspondence of the Hastings Center and of its founder and president, Daniel Callahan. The Hastings Center was founded in 1969 by Daniel Callahan and Willard Gaylin to address the moral problems posed by rapid advances in medicine and biology through a broadly interdisciplinary approach. The center is a nonprofit, nonpartisan organization that carries out educational and research programs on ethical issues in medicine, the life sciences, and the professions.
Hastings Center
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Hastings Center, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, annual reports, grant files, and correspondence of the Hastings Center and of its founder and president, Daniel Callahan. The Hastings Center was founded in 1969 by Daniel Callahan and Willard Gaylin to address the moral problems posed by rapid advances in medicine and biology through a broadly interdisciplinary approach. The center is a nonprofit, nonpartisan organization that carries out educational and research programs on ethical issues in medicine, the life sciences, and the professions.
Bioethics; Medical ethics; Callahan, Daniel, 1930-; Gaylin, Willard; Hastings Center
- Accession 1995-M-182
  - Minutes and annual reports, 1969-1988 (Box 1)
  - Grant files, Circa 1969-1988
    - A - Carnegie (Box 2)
    - Ca - E (Box 3)
    - F - Ford (Box 4)
    - Fou - J.M. (Box 5)
    - Johnson, Robert Wood - Kresge (Box 6)
    - L - National Center (Box 7)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 8)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 9)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 10)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 11)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 12)
    - National Institute of Mental Health - Nuffield (Box 13)
    - O - Rockefeller (Box 14)
    - Rockefeller - S (Box 15)
    - Un - W (Box 16)
  - Correspondence
    - 1969 - 1970; 1971 - 1974, A - E (Box 17)
    - 1971 - 1974, F - M (Box 18)
    - 1971 - 1974, M - V (Box 19)
    - 1971 - 1974, W - Z; 1974, A - Z Misc. (Box 20)
    - 1975 - 1976, A - I (Box 21)
    - 1975 - 1976, K - S (Box 22)
    - 1975 - 1976, S - Z (Box 23)
    - 1977, A - Z (Box 24)
    - 1978, A - Z (Box 25)
    - 1979, A - S (Box 26)
    - 1979, T - Z; 1980, A - P (Box 27)
    - 1980, R - Z; 1981, A - N (Box 28)
    - 1981, O - Z; 1982, A - M (Box 29)
    - 1982, N - Z; 1983, A - M (Box 30)
    - 1983, N - Z; 1984, A - G (Box 31)
    - 1984, H - Z (Box 32)
    - 1985, A - M (Box 33)
    - 1985, N - Z (Box 34)
    - 1986 (Box 35)
    - 1987, A - M (Box 36)
    - 1987, N - Z; Reeves, David, 1983, 1987; Lagerlof, Jan, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - 1988, A - M (Box 38)
    - 1988, N - Z; Reeves, David, 1984, 1988 (Box 39)